<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>D3 for Git</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</guid><description>Background I have had a lot of discussions regarding the teaching of git This is mostly as a part of the SoftwareCarpentries, or in view of my involvement with univ.ai, or simply in every public space I am associated with Without getting into my views, I just wanted to keep this resource in mind The site Learning git is a highly contentious thing People seem to be fond of GUI tools, especially since on non *nix systems, it seems that there is a lot of debate surrounding obtaining the git utility in the first place One of the best ways of understanding (without installing stuff) the mental models required for working with git is this site</description></item><item><title>Shorter Posts</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</guid><description>Background Sometime this year, I realized that I no longer have access to a lot of my older communication. This included, a lot of resources I enjoyed and shared with the people who were around me at that point in time. To counter this, I have decided to opt for shorter posts, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t always include the same level of detail I would prefer to provide.
Alternatives I have an automated system based around IFTTT combined with Twitter, Diigo, and even Pocket However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really tell me much, and trawling through a massive glut of data is often pointless as well There&amp;rsquo;s always Twitter, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really care to hear the views of others when I want to revisit my own ideas Conclusions I will be making shorter posts here, like the random one on octobox</description></item><item><title>Pandora and Proxychains</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pandora-proxychains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 05:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pandora-proxychains/</guid><description>Background Pandora doesn&amp;rsquo;t work outside the states I keep forgetting how to set-up proxychains Proxychains Technically this article expects proxychains-ng, which seems to be the more up-to-date fork of the original proxychains.
Install proxychains-ng
# I am on archlinux.. sudo pacman -S proxychains-ng Copy the configuration to the $HOME directory
cp /etc/proxychains.conf . Edit said configuration to add some US-based proxy
In my particular case, I don&amp;rsquo;t keep the tor section enabled.</description></item><item><title>Replacing Jupyter with Orgmode</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/jupyter-orgmode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/jupyter-orgmode/</guid><description>Background I dislike Jupyter notebooks (and JupyterHub) a lot EIN is really not much of a solution either In the past I have written some posts on TeX with JupyterHub and discussed ways to use virtual Python with JupyterHub in a more reasonable manner.
However, I personally found that EIN was a huge pain to work with, and I mostly ended up working with the web-interface anyway.
It is a bit redundant to do so, given that at-least for my purposes, the end result was a LaTeX document.</description></item><item><title>Poetry and Direnv</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/poetry-direnv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/poetry-direnv/</guid><description>Background I end up writing about using poetry a lot I almost always use direnv in real life too I don&amp;rsquo;t keep writing mini scripts in my .envrc Honestly there&amp;rsquo;s nothing here anyone using the direnv wiki will find surprising, but then it is still neat to link back to.
Setting Up Poetry This essentially works by simply modifying the global .direnvrc which essentially gets sourced by every local .</description></item><item><title>Taming Github Notifications</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ghnotif/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 11:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ghnotif/</guid><description>Background As a member of several large organizations, I get a lot of github notifications. Not all of these are of relevance to me. This is especially true of psuedo-monorepo style repositories like the JOSS review system and especially the exercism community.
I recently (re-)joined the exercism community as a maintainer for the C++ lessons after having been a (sporadic) teacher This was largely in response to a community call to action as the group needed new blood to usher in v3 of the exercism project Anyway, I have since found that at the small cost of possibly much of my public repo data, I can manage my notifications better with Octobox</description></item></channel></rss>