<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ramblings on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/ramblings/</link><description>Recent content in ramblings on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Presentation Supplements for FortranCon'21</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortrancon-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortrancon-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on twin presentations on F2PY and LFortran at FortranCon'21
Background I had the honor and pleasure to have two presentations at the second annual FortranCon in 2021. The fun part was both talks featured the language standard prominently, but were meant to form two sides of a coin.
f2py: Two Decades Later Co-Authors Dr. Ralf Gommers (Quansight Labs), Dr. Melissa Mendonca (Quansight Labs), Dr. Pearu Peterson (Quansight Labs) Duration 20 minutes (15 + 5) Abstract f2py is the gold standard for interfacing Fortran and Python.</description></item><item><title>Presentation Supplements for Greens Function School</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/leshouches-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/leshouches-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on an oral presentation around Fortran and languages
Background I was a participant at the 2021 Les Houches school of physics on &amp;ldquo;Green&amp;rsquo;s function approach to multiple scattering theory in electronic structure and spectroscopies&amp;rdquo;. I opted to give a student talk on programming languages and elementary functions as a cautionary tale for IEEE 754.
Details Title Programming Language Interstices Abstract In this short talk I will discuss the changing landscape of programming languages from the viewpoint of “mixed language” bindings.</description></item><item><title>Regarding Quansight Labs</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/joining-quansight-labs21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 02:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/joining-quansight-labs21/</guid><description>Towards sustainable FOSS with Quansight Labs
Background Rumors of my affiliation with Quansight Labs are indeed true. I have had the pleasure of joining the Labs division as a software engineer 1, whose philosophy is fantastically and succintly described by their director Dr. Ralf Gommers. This means, in nutshell, that in my spare time I will be able to contribute to the continued maintenance of key FOSS projects.</description></item><item><title>42nd Annual Confereence of the Tex Users Group</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/tug-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/tug-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on social events and my presentation at TUG21
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, but with some added shilling; since TUG is fantastic. Plus like the last year, I was gven the opportunity to coordiate social events with Jennifer Claudio.
Social Events Since the 41st TUG in 2020; there is a Zulip instance which is active all year round 1 Can be joined here This year there was a Topia instance for more &amp;ldquo;pseudo-real&amp;rdquo; interactions Details sent to people who registered (free) Slides Title Continuous Integration and TeX with Org-Mode In this talk I would like to introduce the usage of TeX and templates along with generating ad-hoc class and style files for working with orgmode.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for SERI'21</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/seri-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/seri-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on a talk I was to give at SERI'21
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details SERI or the Software Engineering Research in India meeting is the only informal event dedicated to software engineering in the subcontinent, so it was rather gratifying to be accepted, and, to present on Modern documentation across languages.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for IOP CAPS'21 Webdev Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-caps-webdev-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-caps-webdev-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the IOP CAPS'21 student conference on Web Development for Physicists
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Workshop listing on conference site Blurb:</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for Code In Place 2021 SL Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/cip-2021-slw-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 07:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/cip-2021-slw-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the Section Leaders of Code in Place 2021 entitled &amp;ldquo;Wrangling Pythons with Nix for Reproducible Purity&amp;rdquo;
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Blurb verbatim from the spreadsheet.</description></item><item><title>Fortran, GSoC21 and Me</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortran-gsoc-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 05:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortran-gsoc-me/</guid><description>Reminisces and prophecies brought upon by LFortran and GSoC 2021
Background I know not what the language of the future will look like, but I know it will be called FORTRAN&amp;hellip; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;mdash; Charles Anthony Richard Hoare, circa 1982 &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;ndash; Daan Frenkel, 2020
This post is a little belated, given that the GSoC announcements were a few days ago. Therein lies the future, and much digital ink, sweat and blood shall be spilled towards accomplishing the goals outlined in my accepted project proposal.</description></item><item><title>Dotfiles from dotgit to bombadil</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/dotfiles-dotgit-bombadil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/dotfiles-dotgit-bombadil/</guid><description>Discussion on dotfile management, a meandering path to my current setup from dotgit to bombadil. EDIT: Superseded by my chezmoi configuration described here
Background No one gets very far working with stock one-size fits all tools in any discipline but it is especially true of working with computers. The right set of dotfiles have been compared to priming spells for invocation later, and this is probably true. More than anything else, dotfiles offer familiarity where there is none, be it from cowsay or a fancy shell prompt 1.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for IOP's C++ Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-cpp-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-cpp-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the IOP student community on Intermediate C++
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Blurb verbatim from the workshop announcement.</description></item><item><title>SymEngine and the Season of Docs</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/symengine-gsod20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/symengine-gsod20/</guid><description>An overview of documentation complexity and an analysis of incentives.
Background As mentioned a few times before, last year a proposal of mine to improve the documentation for the SymEngine organization was accepted under the Google Season of Docs 2020 initiative. This is a more personal and expanded discussion on the report submitted on the SymEngine Wiki regarding the goals and completion metrics.
Figure 1: Promotional image Google seemed to strongly suggest</description></item><item><title>My Life in E-ink</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 01:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</guid><description>Collection of odds and ends relating to e-readers including personal reminisces
Background Reading has been a huge part of my life. The written word has had arguably more of an impact on my life than anything I have experienced in person. As a kid back in early 2000&amp;rsquo;s; this meant a lot of library trips and saving for paperbacks. I also caught the first wave of the e-ink revolution.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for NixCon 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my lightning talk at NixCon 2020
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Title Nix from the dark ages (without Root) Proposal See the cfp response here Abstract Short comments from the trenches of High Performance Clusters on working with Nix on kernel locked-in systems without proot support.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for PyCon India 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020
Background I am to present at PyCon IN 2020. Some of the motivating reasons for having a post are:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details of this happy circumstance are reproduced below from the CFP here.</description></item><item><title>Grant Proposals - I</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/grant-proposals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/grant-proposals/</guid><description>Personal recollections of the academic grant writing process.
Background Of the many types of writing one undertakes in a typical academic career, grant writing stands out as a rather large anomaly. For the purposes of this post, we will note that an academic writing taxonomy would consist of roughly:
Coursework and Assignments These are more or less comparative writing exercises, where the only main thing which is enforced is (or should be) plagiarism checks.</description></item><item><title>LineageOS Maintainer Appreciation</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</guid><description>A post on a surprisingly heartwarming community appreciation effort.
Background As probably anyone who has asked me about my programming experience has heard, my first real foray into the FOSS community was being a LineageOS co-maintainer (as HaoZeke) for the Xperia Z5 Dual. I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about the community all that much for a few years, mostly since XDA became pretty toxic, and Android development just got, less exciting.</description></item><item><title>Site Rationale</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</guid><description>Why this site exists I have a lot of online presences. I have been around (or at-least, lurking) for over ten years. Almost as long as I have been programming. Anyway, I have a penchant lately for using emacs and honestly there isn&amp;rsquo;t very good support for org-mode files. There are options recently with gatsby as well, but this seemed kinda neat.
What &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo; is This site is built by Hugo The posts are generated with ox-hugo The theme is based of this excellent one by Djordje Atlialp, which in turn is based off of this theme by panr My modifications are here What is here Mostly random thoughts I don&amp;rsquo;t mind people knowing Some tech stuff which isn&amp;rsquo;t coherent enough to be put in any form with references Emacs specific workflows which I might want to write about more than short notes on the config What isn&amp;rsquo;t here Some collections should and will go to my grimoire My doom-emacs configuration Academic stuff is better tracked on Publons or Google Scholar or my pages hosted by my favorite IITK group or UI group</description></item><item><title>Collection of WebLinks</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</guid><description>An attempt to re-claim and verify my digital presence.
Background I mentioned on my about page, that it is nigh impossible to keep track of every digital trace there is of me. That said, it is really not even a countable infinite set yet, so it is a good idea to get started before it gets much worse. This is minimally curated, and will only be sporadically updated, so take everything here with a grain of salt.</description></item></channel></rss>