<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>keyboard on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/keyboard/</link><description>Recent content in keyboard on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Icelandic with Compose Keys on Linux</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/xcompose-keys-linux-icelandic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/xcompose-keys-linux-icelandic/</guid><description>Minimally expanding my existing layouts for supporting Icelandic orthography.1
Background Life outside Emacs can be daunting for a lot of reasons, the lack of auctex and org-latex being a major one. Additionally, for the purposes of my (somewhat current) country of residence2, it is often useful to be able to type Icelandic characters without resorting to something like typeit.
Compositional Choices I already use klfc to generate a very portable (in a Unix sense) customized VIM based Colemak binding layout.</description></item><item><title>Remapping Keys with XKB and KLFC</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</guid><description>An introduction to hacking keyboard layouts with X keyboard extension (XKB) and klfc, focused on Colemak and vim bindings
Background In-spite of maximizing ergonomic bindings for most common software (e.g. Vimium, doom-emacs), every operation with the arrow keys still trouble me. Here I will lay out my experiments transitioning to a stable, uniquely defined setup with the X keyboard extension.
Keyboard Basics Some terms to keep in mind for this post are1:</description></item></channel></rss>