<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>archlinux on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/archlinux/</link><description>Recent content in archlinux on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/archlinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Laptop setup notes btrfs subvolumes</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/laptop-setup-btrfs-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/laptop-setup-btrfs-notes/</guid><description>Thoughts on laptop configurations for ArchLinux in 2023, with btrfs and sway
Warning
This post is a little less complete than most, it has been dated to roughly the correct time chronologically.
Background I split this post from the previous one, to make each more self contained. Since the installation media has more features one might perhaps use gparted for resizing disks, use the GUI for managing networks, etc. Personally I generally allocate a chunk from whatever other OS is present in gparted, and format it as unformatted.</description></item><item><title>Customizing ArchLinux Installation Media</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/customizing-archlinux-im/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/customizing-archlinux-im/</guid><description>A short plug for hzArchiso, and general thoughts on archiso
Background I recently had to switch server boxes, due to a cascade of hardware errors stemming from a remodeling of my home. The new box, however, did not see fit to include a WiFi card, which meant I had to add one of my own, a Realtek 88XXau, the kernel module for which is on the AUR.
This meant the official ArchLinux ISO would not be able to connect to the internet, and short of copying over files from PC to PC manually with a USB stick, my only option was to build my own installation media.</description></item><item><title>Revisiting Wayland for ArchLinux</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/revisiting-wayland-2021-archlinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/revisiting-wayland-2021-archlinux/</guid><description>Ruminating on wayland and sway for daily use with ArchLinux
Background Many years ago, I found time to make an attempt to switch away from the X11 Window system to Wayland. At the time, I ended up switching back to Xorg, but I did want to revisit it. Since I returned from home recently and was gifted a Gen 6 ThinkPad X1 Carbon, I had a perfect opportunity to do so 1.</description></item></channel></rss>