<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on Rohit Goswami</title><link>/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 21:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SymEngine and the Season of Docs</title><link>/posts/symengine-gsod20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/symengine-gsod20/</guid><description>An overview of documentation complexity and an analysis of incentives.
Background As mentioned a few times before, last year a proposal of mine to improve the documentation for the SymEngine organization was accepted under the Google Season of Docs 2020 initiative. This is a more personal and expanded discussion on the report submitted on the SymEngine Wiki regarding the goals and completion metrics.
Figure 1: Promotional image Google seemed to strongly suggest</description></item><item><title>Grant Proposals - I</title><link>/posts/grant-proposals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/grant-proposals/</guid><description>Personal recollections of the academic grant writing process.
Background Of the many types of writing one undertakes in a typical academic career, grant writing stands out as a rather large anomaly. For the purposes of this post, we will note that an academic writing taxonomy would consist of roughly:
Coursework and Assignments These are more or less comparative writing exercises, where the only main thing which is enforced is (or should be) plagiarism checks.</description></item><item><title>LineageOS Maintainer Appreciation</title><link>/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</guid><description>A post on a surprisingly heartwarming community appreciation effort.
Background As probably anyone who has asked me about my programming experience has heard, my first real foray into the FOSS community was being a LineageOS co-maintainer (as HaoZeke) for the Xperia Z5 Dual. I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about the community all that much for a few years, mostly since XDA became pretty toxic, and Android development just got, less exciting.</description></item><item><title>Bojack Horseman</title><link>/posts/bojack-horseman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/bojack-horseman/</guid><description>Background For a while I was worried about writing about a TV show here. I thought it might be frivolous, or worse, might outweigh the other kinds of articles I would like to write. However, like most things, that which is ignored just grows, so it is easier to just write and forget about it.
The Show Much has been said about how Bojack Horseman is one of the best shows ever, and they&amp;rsquo;re all correct.</description></item></channel></rss>