<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>explanations on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/explanations/</link><description>Recent content in explanations on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/explanations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching to Colemak</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid><description>Thoughts on and rationale behind leaving QWERTY and touch typing in general. Followed by this post on refactoring my Dotfiles.
Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to Colemak but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.</description></item><item><title>Site Rationale</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</guid><description>Why this site exists I have a lot of online presences. I have been around (or at-least, lurking) for over ten years. Almost as long as I have been programming. Anyway, I have a penchant lately for using emacs and honestly there isn&amp;rsquo;t very good support for org-mode files. There are options recently with gatsby as well, but this seemed kinda neat.
What &amp;lsquo;this&amp;rsquo; is This site is built by Hugo The posts are generated with ox-hugo The theme is based of this excellent one by Djordje Atlialp, which in turn is based off of this theme by panr My modifications are here What is here Mostly random thoughts I don&amp;rsquo;t mind people knowing Some tech stuff which isn&amp;rsquo;t coherent enough to be put in any form with references Emacs specific workflows which I might want to write about more than short notes on the config What isn&amp;rsquo;t here Some collections should and will go to my grimoire My doom-emacs configuration Academic stuff is better tracked on Publons or Google Scholar or my pages hosted by my favorite IITK group or UI group</description></item></channel></rss>