<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conferences on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/categories/conferences/</link><description>Recent content in conferences on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Presentation Supplements for FortranCon'21</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortrancon-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortrancon-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on twin presentations on F2PY and LFortran at FortranCon'21
Background I had the honor and pleasure to have two presentations at the second annual FortranCon in 2021. The fun part was both talks featured the language standard prominently, but were meant to form two sides of a coin.
f2py: Two Decades Later Co-Authors Dr. Ralf Gommers (Quansight Labs), Dr. Melissa Mendonca (Quansight Labs), Dr. Pearu Peterson (Quansight Labs) Duration 20 minutes (15 + 5) Abstract f2py is the gold standard for interfacing Fortran and Python.</description></item><item><title>Presentation Supplements for Greens Function School</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/leshouches-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/leshouches-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on an oral presentation around Fortran and languages
Background I was a participant at the 2021 Les Houches school of physics on &amp;ldquo;Green&amp;rsquo;s function approach to multiple scattering theory in electronic structure and spectroscopies&amp;rdquo;. I opted to give a student talk on programming languages and elementary functions as a cautionary tale for IEEE 754.
Details Title Programming Language Interstices Abstract In this short talk I will discuss the changing landscape of programming languages from the viewpoint of “mixed language” bindings.</description></item><item><title>42nd Annual Confereence of the Tex Users Group</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/tug-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/tug-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on social events and my presentation at TUG21
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, but with some added shilling; since TUG is fantastic. Plus like the last year, I was gven the opportunity to coordiate social events with Jennifer Claudio.
Social Events Since the 41st TUG in 2020; there is a Zulip instance which is active all year round 1 Can be joined here This year there was a Topia instance for more &amp;ldquo;pseudo-real&amp;rdquo; interactions Details sent to people who registered (free) Slides Title Continuous Integration and TeX with Org-Mode In this talk I would like to introduce the usage of TeX and templates along with generating ad-hoc class and style files for working with orgmode.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for SERI'21</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/seri-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/seri-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on a talk I was to give at SERI'21
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details SERI or the Software Engineering Research in India meeting is the only informal event dedicated to software engineering in the subcontinent, so it was rather gratifying to be accepted, and, to present on Modern documentation across languages.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for IOP CAPS'21 Webdev Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-caps-webdev-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-caps-webdev-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the IOP CAPS'21 student conference on Web Development for Physicists
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Workshop listing on conference site Blurb:</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for Code In Place 2021 SL Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/cip-2021-slw-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 07:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/cip-2021-slw-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the Section Leaders of Code in Place 2021 entitled &amp;ldquo;Wrangling Pythons with Nix for Reproducible Purity&amp;rdquo;
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Blurb verbatim from the spreadsheet.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for IOP's C++ Workshop</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-cpp-2021-meta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/iop-cpp-2021-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on the workshop I held for the IOP student community on Intermediate C++
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my other presentation meta-posts, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Blurb verbatim from the workshop announcement.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for NixCon 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my lightning talk at NixCon 2020
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Title Nix from the dark ages (without Root) Proposal See the cfp response here Abstract Short comments from the trenches of High Performance Clusters on working with Nix on kernel locked-in systems without proot support.</description></item><item><title>Talk Supplements for PyCon India 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020
Background I am to present at PyCon IN 2020. Some of the motivating reasons for having a post are:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details of this happy circumstance are reproduced below from the CFP here.</description></item></channel></rss>