<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cpp on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/cpp/</link><description>Recent content in cpp on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/cpp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publishing Doxygen and Sphinx with Nix and Rake</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pub-doc-cpp-dox-sph-nix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pub-doc-cpp-dox-sph-nix/</guid><description>Automating documenation deployment with Travis, rake and nix
Background In the previous post we generated documentation using Doxygen with Exhale to handle Sphinx. Now we will clean up the earlier workflow with rake and ensure the environment is reproducible with nix while deploying to Travis CI.
Series Documenting C++ with Doxygen and Sphinx - Exhale Publishing Doxygen and Sphinx with Nix and Rake &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; You are here Documenting C++ with Doxygen and Sphinx - doxyrest Adding Tutorials to Sphinx Projects Setup A quick reminder of the setup we generated in the last post:</description></item><item><title>Documenting C++ with Doxygen and Sphinx - Exhale</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/doc-cpp-dox-sph-exhale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 06:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/doc-cpp-dox-sph-exhale/</guid><description>This post outlines a basic workflow for C++ projects using Doxygen, Sphinx, and Exhale.
Background My project proposal for documenting Symengine was recently accepted for the Google Summer of Docs initiative. In the past I have been more than happy to document C++ code using only Doxygen (with pretty fantastic results), while keeping example usage separate (d-SEAMS wiki). Though this is still a feasible method, a monolithic multi-project setup might benefit from Sphinx, which is what will be covered.</description></item></channel></rss>