<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hpc on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/hpc/</link><description>Recent content in hpc on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/hpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Talk Supplements for NixCon 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/nixcon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my lightning talk at NixCon 2020
Background Much the same as the rationale behind my meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020, that is:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details Title Nix from the dark ages (without Root) Proposal See the cfp response here Abstract Short comments from the trenches of High Performance Clusters on working with Nix on kernel locked-in systems without proot support.</description></item><item><title>Local Nix without Root</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/local-nix-no-root/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/local-nix-no-root/</guid><description>Monkeying around with nix for HPC systems which have no root access and NFS filesystems.
Background Nix is not well known for being friendly to users without root access. This is typically made worse by the &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; filesystem attributes common to HPC networks (this also plagues hermes). An earlier post details how and why proot failed. The short pitch is simply:
Figure 1: Does your HPC look like this?</description></item><item><title>HPC Dotfiles and LMod</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/hpc-dots-lmod/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 02:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/hpc-dots-lmod/</guid><description>Background My move away from the powerful, but unimaginatively named HPC clusters of IITK 1 brought me in close contact with the Lua based 2 lmod module system. Rather than fall into the rabbit hole of brew we will leverage the existing system to add our new libraries. Not finding any good collections of these composable environments, and having failed once before to install Nix as a user without admin access, I decided to start my own collection of Lmod recipies.</description></item><item><title>Provisioning Dotfiles on an HPC</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</guid><description>Background My dotfiles turned 4 years old a few months ago (since 9th Jan 2017) and remains one of my most frequently updated projects for obvious reasons. Going through the changes reminds me of a whole of posts I never got around to writing.
Anyway, recently I gained access to another HPC cluster, with a standard configuration (bash, old CentOS) and decided to track my provisioning steps. This is really a very streamlined experience by now, since I&amp;rsquo;ve used the same setup across scores of machines.</description></item></channel></rss>