<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>teaching on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/teaching/</link><description>Recent content in teaching on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LosslessCut, Zoom and an AMA for CS106A</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/losslesscut-zoom-ama/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/losslesscut-zoom-ama/</guid><description>Background I recently had the opportunity to take part in an AMA (ask me anything) session for the CS106A students on Machine Learning for the Physical Sciences. This is a post about the technical issues, and also includes a video if you read through.
Zoom and LosslessCut Zoom recordings are one of the nicer ways to deal with switching windows and screen sharing, especially after fixing the dark screen glitch. However, though LosslessCut works really well to get cut-points, exporting and merging the file into one caused a bunch of glitches.</description></item><item><title>CS106A Small Group Training</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-trainig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-trainig/</guid><description>Background As I mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. This post relates to the notes and thoughts garnered during the small group training session1.
Reflections Demographics Redacted. Did not use breakout meetings due to privacy issues.
Engagement and Participation Some people were more active (skewed responses) Some of the more rudimentary questions might have been suppressed Highlighted Moments Covering multiple perspectives Different mental models Challenges and Transformations Technical debt was an issue Lack of engagement Went on for too long For me in particular:</description></item><item><title>CS106A Section Meeting I</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-meet1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 22:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-meet1/</guid><description>Background As I mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. I did also mention I&amp;rsquo;d try to keep a set of short notes on the process. I finally had my first section meeting!
Preparation I went through the following:
Sent out a welcome message Detailed the workflow Set up a HackMD instance Set up some slides in beamer1 However, after that, I was still concerned since I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much of a response on the ice-breakers for EdStem.</description></item><item><title>Small Section On-boarding</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp/</guid><description>Background As I mentioned in my last post, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. I did also mention I&amp;rsquo;d try to keep a set of short notes on the process. So there1.
The Training Given the overwhelming number of students, and section leaders, the small groups are for fostering a community of teachers.
Consider allowing for daisy chaining during introductions Discussions are the primary take-away Only the instructor should be coding during the session Core components Clarity Content Atmosphere Section management Correctness Sectional Details Check in at the start Notice the space Check in regularly Avoid negative phrases Establish norms and the general culture Zoom Norms Have people introduce themselves Mute people when they aren&amp;rsquo;t talking Raise hands Try to use icebreakers which respect privacy Materials Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the stuff which, being as it was open-sourced, I suppose is OK to put here2.</description></item><item><title>On-boarding for Code in Place</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</guid><description>Background A few weeks ago, I ended up recording a video for the Stanford CS106A: Code in Place initiative (which can be found here). I heard back a while ago, and am now to lead a section for the course!
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be making a series of short posts as this process continues.
On-Boarding This was very reminiscent of the Carpentries instructor training, which makes sense, given how well thought out that experience was.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Should Get an A - David MacKay</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</guid><description>Background I recently read this post written by the now deceased Prof. David MacKay 1 It should be read widely, however, given that it is distributed as a ps.gz which is then a .ps file, and thus probably inaccessible to many of the people who should read it, I decided to rework it for native online consumption (there is also a pdf) THIS IS NOT MY CONTENT 2 Now, enjoy the post Everyone Should Get an A Imagine a University – call it Camwick – where all students arrive with straight A grades.</description></item></channel></rss>