<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Talk Supplements for PyCon India 2020</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pycon-in-2020-meta/</guid><description>A meta-post on my talk at PyCon India 2020
Background I am to present at PyCon IN 2020. Some of the motivating reasons for having a post are:
I would like to preserve questions I would like to collect the video, slides and other miscellaneous stuff in one location 1 It would be nice to have my own thoughts here afterwards Details of this happy circumstance are reproduced below from the CFP here.</description></item><item><title>Niv and Mach-Nix for Nix Python</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mach-nix-niv-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 05:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mach-nix-niv-python/</guid><description>Short post on using mach-nix with niv.
Background In previous posts, there was a discussion on a ground up approach to adding packages which aren&amp;rsquo;t on the core nixpkgs channels using GitHub or PyPi sources. However, this lacked a way to do so programmatically, and also a way to convert existing python projects.
Python Dependency Management This time, instead of the more pedagogical approach of building packages from PyPi or GitHub, we will use overlays and the excellent mach-nix to speed up the process.</description></item><item><title>A Tutorial Introduction to Nix</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ccon-tut-nix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ccon-tut-nix/</guid><description>Brief introduction to a nix based project workflow.
Background For CarpentryCon@Home 2020, along with Amrita Goswami, I am to prepare and deliver a workshop on &amp;ldquo;Reproducible Environments with the Nix Packaging System&amp;rdquo;. In particular, as a community of practice lesson, the focus is not on packaging (as is typical of most Nix tutorials) nor on the Nix expression language itself, but instead on the use of Nix as a replacement for virtual environments using mkShell.</description></item><item><title>Poetry and Direnv</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/poetry-direnv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/poetry-direnv/</guid><description>Background I end up writing about using poetry a lot I almost always use direnv in real life too I don&amp;rsquo;t keep writing mini scripts in my .envrc Honestly there&amp;rsquo;s nothing here anyone using the direnv wiki will find surprising, but then it is still neat to link back to.
Setting Up Poetry This essentially works by simply modifying the global .direnvrc which essentially gets sourced by every local .</description></item></channel></rss>