<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in books on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 13:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing cloud based calibre libraries</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/managing-cloud-based-calibre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/managing-cloud-based-calibre/</guid><description>Ruminations on cross-cloud library management
Background I have a set of different devices across which I need to sync my library (described in an earlier post). Ideally this should be a lazy synchronization mechanism and be as general as possible.
Constraints calibre should never be modifying the files while they are being synced, not only because it creates and removes a lot of temporary files and folders which will cause churn, but also because it actually locks files during modification and this leads to permission issues.</description></item><item><title>My Life in E-ink</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 01:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</guid><description>Collection of odds and ends relating to e-readers including personal reminisces
Background Reading has been a huge part of my life. The written word has had arguably more of an impact on my life than anything I have experienced in person. As a kid back in early 2000&amp;rsquo;s; this meant a lot of library trips and saving for paperbacks. I also caught the first wave of the e-ink revolution. Nothing beats a real book, in terms of textures and scents; but e-ink devices and the fantastic tools outlined here should make reading digital books much more palpable 1.</description></item></channel></rss>