<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 02:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Regarding Quansight Labs</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/joining-quansight-labs21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 02:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/joining-quansight-labs21/</guid><description>Towards sustainable FOSS with Quansight Labs
Background Rumors of my affiliation with Quansight Labs are indeed true. I have had the pleasure of joining the Labs division as a software engineer 1, whose philosophy is fantastically and succintly described by their director Dr. Ralf Gommers. This means, in nutshell, that in my spare time I will be able to contribute to the continued maintenance of key FOSS projects.</description></item><item><title>Remapping Keys for ColemakVIM on MacOS</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/keybindings-colevimhz-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/keybindings-colevimhz-macos/</guid><description>Struggling to emulate klfc for VIM Colemak bindings on Darwin (macOS) systems with Hammerspoon and Karabiner
Background I have mentioned in the past my customized Colemak dotfiles which I used with a customized keyboard layout. Unfortunately, the .keylayout system of MacOS is far more primitive than the elegant klfc setup 1. For an understanding of what we are trying to get at, the following poorly made video will suffice.</description></item><item><title>Fortran, GSoC21 and Me</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortran-gsoc-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 05:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fortran-gsoc-me/</guid><description>Reminisces and prophecies brought upon by LFortran and GSoC 2021
Background I know not what the language of the future will look like, but I know it will be called FORTRAN&amp;hellip; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;mdash; Charles Anthony Richard Hoare, circa 1982 &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;ndash; Daan Frenkel, 2020
This post is a little belated, given that the GSoC announcements were a few days ago. Therein lies the future, and much digital ink, sweat and blood shall be spilled towards accomplishing the goals outlined in my accepted project proposal.</description></item><item><title>Dotfiles from dotgit to bombadil</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/dotfiles-dotgit-bombadil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/dotfiles-dotgit-bombadil/</guid><description>Discussion on dotfile management, a meandering path to my current setup from dotgit to bombadil. EDIT: Superseded by my chezmoi configuration described here
Background No one gets very far working with stock one-size fits all tools in any discipline but it is especially true of working with computers. The right set of dotfiles have been compared to priming spells for invocation later, and this is probably true. More than anything else, dotfiles offer familiarity where there is none, be it from cowsay or a fancy shell prompt 1.</description></item><item><title>Free Software and Me</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fsf-me-stallman/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/fsf-me-stallman/</guid><description>Thoughts about the FSF, toxicity, and Stallman
First a disclaimer. Comments are not enabled for this post. This is very personal, and it is in my online space so I reserve the right to not talk about this. This is not a conversation. It is a protracted comment on recent, disappointing, news about the &amp;ldquo;tech community&amp;rdquo;. It is unlike anything I have normally published; and is hopefully the last time I will publish something like this.</description></item><item><title>SymEngine and the Season of Docs</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/symengine-gsod20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/symengine-gsod20/</guid><description>An overview of documentation complexity and an analysis of incentives.
Background As mentioned a few times before, last year a proposal of mine to improve the documentation for the SymEngine organization was accepted under the Google Season of Docs 2020 initiative. This is a more personal and expanded discussion on the report submitted on the SymEngine Wiki regarding the goals and completion metrics.
Figure 1: Promotional image Google seemed to strongly suggest</description></item><item><title>My Life in E-ink</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 01:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</guid><description>Collection of odds and ends relating to e-readers including personal reminisces
Background Reading has been a huge part of my life. The written word has had arguably more of an impact on my life than anything I have experienced in person. As a kid back in early 2000&amp;rsquo;s; this meant a lot of library trips and saving for paperbacks. I also caught the first wave of the e-ink revolution.</description></item><item><title>Reclaiming Email with Astroid</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/reclaim-email-astroid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/reclaim-email-astroid/</guid><description>Migrating Imap, Gmail and Exchange, mail accounts from GUI clients to Astroid
Background Initially, I had planned this post to start with a brief history of the decline of email clients for Linux. That quickly got out of hand, and was therefore spun out into a post of its own (TBD). To keep things brief. Thanks to the incredible ineptitude of the Thunderbird steering committee, I ended up requiring a new mail client.</description></item><item><title>Remapping Keys with XKB and KLFC</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</guid><description>An introduction to hacking keyboard layouts with X keyboard extension (XKB) and klfc, focused on Colemak and vim bindings
Background Inspite of maximizing ergonomic bindings for most common software (e.g. Vimium, doom-emacs), every operation with the arrow keys still trouble me. Here I will lay out my experiments transitioning to a stable, uniquely defined setup with the X keyboard extension.
Series This post is part of a series on Colemak and keyboard management in general.</description></item><item><title>Grant Proposals - I</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/grant-proposals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/grant-proposals/</guid><description>Personal recollections of the academic grant writing process.
Background Of the many types of writing one undertakes in a typical academic career, grant writing stands out as a rather large anomaly. For the purposes of this post, we will note that an academic writing taxonomy would consist of roughly:
Coursework and Assignments These are more or less comparative writing exercises, where the only main thing which is enforced is (or should be) plagiarism checks.</description></item><item><title>LineageOS Maintainer Appreciation</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/linos-maintainer-appre/</guid><description>A post on a surprisingly heartwarming community appreciation effort.
Background As probably anyone who has asked me about my programming experience has heard, my first real foray into the FOSS community was being a LineageOS co-maintainer (as HaoZeke) for the Xperia Z5 Dual. I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about the community all that much for a few years, mostly since XDA became pretty toxic, and Android development just got, less exciting.</description></item><item><title>Switching to Colemak</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid><description>Thoughts on and rationale behind leaving QWERTY and touch typing in general. Followed by this post on refactoring my Dotfiles.
Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to Colemak but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.</description></item><item><title>Bojack Horseman</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/bojack-horseman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/bojack-horseman/</guid><description>Background For a while I was worried about writing about a TV show here. I thought it might be frivolous, or worse, might outweigh the other kinds of articles I would like to write. However, like most things, that which is ignored just grows, so it is easier to just write and forget about it.
The Show Much has been said about how Bojack Horseman is one of the best shows ever, and they&amp;rsquo;re all correct.</description></item><item><title>Pandora and Proxychains</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pandora-proxychains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 05:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/pandora-proxychains/</guid><description>Background Pandora doesn&amp;rsquo;t work outside the states I keep forgetting how to set-up proxychains Proxychains Technically this article expects proxychains-ng, which seems to be the more up-to-date fork of the original proxychains.
Install proxychains-ng 1# I am on archlinux.. 2sudo pacman -S proxychains-ng Copy the configuration to the $HOME directory 1cp /etc/proxychains.conf . Edit said configuration to add some US-based proxy In my particular case, I don&amp;rsquo;t keep the tor section enabled.</description></item><item><title>Site Rationale</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</guid><description>Why this site exists I have a lot of online presences. I have been around (or at-least, lurking) for over ten years. Almost as long as I have been programming. Anyway, I have a penchant lately for using emacs and honestly there isn&amp;rsquo;t very good support for org-mode files. There are options recently with gatsby as well, but this seemed kinda neat.
What &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo; is This site is built by Hugo The posts are generated with ox-hugo The theme is based of this excellent one by Djordje Atlialp, which in turn is based off of this theme by panr My modifications are here What is here Mostly random thoughts I don&amp;rsquo;t mind people knowing Some tech stuff which isn&amp;rsquo;t coherent enough to be put in any form with references Emacs specific workflows which I might want to write about more than short notes on the config What isn&amp;rsquo;t here Some collections should and will go to my grimoire My doom-emacs configuration Academic stuff is better tracked on Publons or Google Scholar or my pages hosted by my favorite IITK group or UI group</description></item><item><title>Collection of WebLinks</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</guid><description>An attempt to re-claim and verify my digital presence.
Background I mentioned on my about page, that it is nigh impossible to keep track of every digital trace there is of me. That said, it is really not even a countable infinite set yet, so it is a good idea to get started before it gets much worse. This is minimally curated, and will only be sporadically updated, so take everything here with a grain of salt.</description></item></channel></rss>