<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colemak necessities on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/series/colemak-necessities/</link><description>Recent content in Colemak necessities on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/series/colemak-necessities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Icelandic with Compose Keys on Linux</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/xcompose-keys-linux-icelandic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/xcompose-keys-linux-icelandic/</guid><description>Minimally expanding my existing layouts for supporting Icelandic orthography.1
Background Life outside Emacs can be daunting for a lot of reasons, the lack of auctex and org-latex being a major one. Additionally, for the purposes of my (somewhat current) country of residence2, it is often useful to be able to type Icelandic characters without resorting to something like typeit.
Compositional Choices I already use klfc to generate a very portable (in a Unix sense) customized VIM based Colemak binding layout.</description></item><item><title>Remapping Keys for ColemakVIM on MacOS</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/keybindings-colevimhz-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/keybindings-colevimhz-macos/</guid><description>Struggling to emulate klfc for VIM Colemak bindings on Darwin (macOS) systems with Hammerspoon and Karabiner
Background I have mentioned in the past my customized Colemak dotfiles which I used with a customized keyboard layout. Unfortunately, the .keylayout system of MacOS is far more primitive than the elegant klfc setup 1. For an understanding of what we are trying to get at, the following poorly made video will suffice.</description></item><item><title>Remapping Keys with XKB and KLFC</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/remap-keys-xkb-klfc/</guid><description>An introduction to hacking keyboard layouts with X keyboard extension (XKB) and klfc, focused on Colemak and vim bindings
Background In-spite of maximizing ergonomic bindings for most common software (e.g. Vimium, doom-emacs), every operation with the arrow keys still trouble me. Here I will lay out my experiments transitioning to a stable, uniquely defined setup with the X keyboard extension.
Keyboard Basics Some terms to keep in mind for this post are1:</description></item><item><title>Refactoring Dotfiles For Colemak</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</guid><description>A more actionable follow up to my personal recollections relating to my switch to Colemak.
Background I have, in the past written about how I made the switch to Colemak. However, until recently, I was still trying to mimic the VIM keybindings from QWERTY. This is a post where I discuss the changes I made to ensure that I never have to stretch my fingers in odd ways again. The main idea is expressed well by vim-colemak.</description></item><item><title>Switching to Colemak</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid><description>Thoughts on and rationale behind leaving QWERTY and touch typing in general. Followed by this post on refactoring my Dotfiles.
Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to Colemak but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.</description></item></channel></rss>