<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ideas on Rohit Goswami</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/ideas/</link><description>Recent content in ideas on Rohit Goswami</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a>.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analytics II: Goat to Clicky</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-clicky/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-clicky/</guid><description>A follow up to my earlier post on analytics, and on migrating from Goat Counter to Clicky.
Background A few days ago I recieved the following email:
Hi there!
I made some changes to the GoatCounter plans/pricing:
GoatCounter now has a &amp;ldquo;Starter&amp;rdquo; plan, this is €5/month, limited to 100k pageviews/month, comes with a custom domain, and allow commercial use. This is mostly the same as the &amp;ldquo;personal plus&amp;rdquo; plan there was before, except that it allows commercial use.</description></item><item><title>On-boarding for Code in Place</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</guid><description>Background A few weeks ago, I ended up recording a video for the Stanford CS106A: Code in Place initiative (which can be found here). I heard back a while ago, and am now to lead a section for the course!
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be making a series of short posts as this process continues.
On-Boarding This was very reminiscent of the Carpentries instructor training, which makes sense, given how well thought out that experience was.</description></item><item><title>Analytics: Google to Goat</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</guid><description>Background Like a lot of my tech based rants, this was brought on by a recent Hacker News post. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into why the product listed there is a hollow faux FOSS rip-off. I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss how the &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; analytics option, like many others are just hobby projects taking pot shots at other projects. Or how insanely overpriced most alternatives are.
I will however discuss why and how I transitioned to using the awesome Goat Counter.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Should Get an A - David MacKay</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</guid><description>Background I recently read this post written by the now deceased Prof. David MacKay 1 It should be read widely, however, given that it is distributed as a ps.gz which is then a .ps file, and thus probably inaccessible to many of the people who should read it, I decided to rework it for native online consumption (there is also a pdf) THIS IS NOT MY CONTENT 2 Now, enjoy the post Everyone Should Get an A Imagine a University – call it Camwick – where all students arrive with straight A grades.</description></item><item><title>D3 for Git</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</guid><description>Background I have had a lot of discussions regarding the teaching of git This is mostly as a part of the SoftwareCarpentries, or in view of my involvement with univ.ai, or simply in every public space I am associated with Without getting into my views, I just wanted to keep this resource in mind The site Learning git is a highly contentious thing People seem to be fond of GUI tools, especially since on non *nix systems, it seems that there is a lot of debate surrounding obtaining the git utility in the first place One of the best ways of understanding (without installing stuff) the mental models required for working with git is this site</description></item><item><title>Shorter Posts</title><link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</guid><description>Background Sometime this year, I realized that I no longer have access to a lot of my older communication. This included, a lot of resources I enjoyed and shared with the people who were around me at that point in time. To counter this, I have decided to opt for shorter posts, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t always include the same level of detail I would prefer to provide.
Alternatives I have an automated system based around IFTTT combined with Twitter, Diigo, and even Pocket However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really tell me much, and trawling through a massive glut of data is often pointless as well There&amp;rsquo;s always Twitter, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really care to hear the views of others when I want to revisit my own ideas Conclusions I will be making shorter posts here, like the random one on octobox</description></item></channel></rss>